To get some practice with marks and filters,
我们来练习一下“标记”(Marks) 和“筛选器”(Filters)
let's say your boss asked you to dig into the data to better understand
假设你的老板要求你深入挖掘数据 以更好地理解数据
what regions had the highest profits in 2014.
2014 年哪些区域的利润最高
To start, let's drag profit into the row shelf and region into the column shelf.
首先 我们将 profit 拖入行功能区 将 Region 拖入列功能区
Now, we need to filter the data to only include 2014.
现在我们需要筛选数据 得到仅包含 2014 年的数据
To do this, let's drag the order date variable into the filters.
要做到这一点 我们要将 order date 变量拖入筛选器中
There are lots of ways to implement a date filter,
实现日期筛选器的方法有多个
but in this case, let's select year here and check 2014.
在这个例子中 我们选择“年”并勾选 2014
To show the filter,
要显示筛选器
let's click the dropdown and select show filter.
我们点击下拉列表并选择“显示筛选器”(Show Filter)
Lastly, let's sort the columns,
最后 我们对图表进行排序
from highest to lowest of the chart is more readable.
在图表中从最高到最低排序更易读
You could do this with this sort button at the top of the screen.
你可以使用屏幕顶部的这个排序按钮进行此操作
Now, let's use some additional variables to help us
现在 使用一些额外的变量
drill down into the product categories.
可以帮助我们深入了解产品类别
Let's start by bringing in the category field.
首先我们引入“类别”(Category) 字段
You can encode this in a variety of ways,
你可以通过多种方式对此进行编码
but the most logical would be to include it in the rows, like this.
但最合乎逻辑的是像这样将其置于行功能区中
Make it a separate bar chart for each category,
使每个类别都生成单独的条形图
or to encode it as color, which we'll do here.
或者用“颜色”对“类别”编码 我们将在这里这么做
When we encode category as color,
当我们用“颜色”来编码“类别”时
you can see a legend appears on the right.
可以看到右边出现了一个图例
We can use this legend to apply filters by clicking on
我们可以利用此图例来操纵筛选器
them and selecting keep only, like this.
方法是点击图例中的“家具”(Furniture) 选择“仅保留”(Keep Only)
Now, we only see the profit data for furniture.
现在 我们就只看到家具的利润数据
This adds a category filter to the filter shelf.
这会向筛选器功能区添加类别筛选器
And, if we want to see it,
如果我们想查看类别筛选器
we can click the dropdown and select show filter.
可以点击下拉列表并选择“显示筛选器”(Show Filter)
Now we're filtered on furniture and let's add subcategory in as color.
我们已筛选出“家具”类别 现在让我们将子类别添加到“颜色”
Now, we can see the profit attributable to each product subcategory by region.
可以看到每个产品子类别按地区划分的利润
You can add additional detail to the chart by encoding data with the tooltip.
你可以通过使用“工具提示”(Tooltip)编码数据来向图表添加其他详细信息
To finish off this part,
要完成本部分
let's add sales data to the tooltip card so when you hover over each section,
我们向“工具提示”卡添加销售数据 这样当你将鼠标悬停在每个部分上时
you can see both the profit and sales.
就会看到利润和销量